<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Eating My Code Everyday</title>
    <link>https://haruair.github.io/blog/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Eating My Code Everyday</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-AU</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 19:11:45 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://haruair.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>column `user_id` cannot be null on django admin</title>
      <link>https://haruair.github.io/post/column-user_id-cannot-be-null-on-django-admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2017 19:11:45 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruair.github.io/post/column-user_id-cannot-be-null-on-django-admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got an IntegrityError when I remove the user from django-admin. I uses custom &lt;code&gt;User&lt;/code&gt; model,
but I didn&amp;rsquo;t change that much rather than &lt;code&gt;AbrstractUser&lt;/code&gt; from &lt;code&gt;django.contrib.auth.models&lt;/code&gt;. The
error was like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;IntegrityError: (1048, &amp;quot;Column &#39;user_id&#39; cannot be null&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the case at all. I asussemed that the error occurs from MySQL, I checked all table
schema one by one and finally found the reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the model includes User &lt;code&gt;ForeignKey&lt;/code&gt; with &lt;code&gt;on_delete=models.SET_DEFAULTS&lt;/code&gt; which is fine
because when remove the user, it will set the default value, &lt;code&gt;None&lt;/code&gt; in this case. This model is the
record for the signing policy so it also includes Policy &lt;code&gt;ForeignKey&lt;/code&gt;. Then these fields sets as
&lt;code&gt;unique_together&lt;/code&gt; that the database create a unique key based on these two fields. When removed
the user, the field followed &lt;code&gt;on_delete&lt;/code&gt; action and tried to remove &lt;code&gt;user_id&lt;/code&gt;, then the update failed
because of the &lt;code&gt;unique_together&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I should be more careful when I use &lt;code&gt;unique_together&lt;/code&gt;, Django is too easy to create this kind of
relationship on the code, especially. With great power comes great responsibility!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s Resolution</title>
      <link>https://haruair.github.io/post/new-years-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 04:11:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://haruair.github.io/post/new-years-resolution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to make a list. New year&amp;rsquo;s resolution is one of the things, I almost
forget about it at the end of the year, though. I want to list some ideas for
2017:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep writing a blog as much as I did last year. But the difference is that the
posts will be written by English.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read more. When I read something, it still very slow. Probably I will grab
Kindle again, want to spend more time with the text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do coding. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything with open source in last year because of the
translation. I want to make something.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list is the three big things in this year. Will see what I can achieve at
the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I want to mention here something, I didn&amp;rsquo;t speak in public just yet. I got
an opportunity from somewhere else. The position is a quite different rather
than the current one. I need to digest new environments and also tech stacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s almost 5 years since I moved in Melbourne. I always said that English is
the important if someone want to live here, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t do any effort
during this period. I did some preparation for IELTS once, that study was not
intence at all because the goal was quite low points. In this time, I want to
study intensively. My expectation of this year is studying like a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://koreanteenlife.wordpress.com/2015/01/22/gosam/&#34;&gt;gosam&lt;/a&gt; does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Practice makes perfect. Everyone knows that, most of people doesn&amp;rsquo;t do that.
I will make it for the perfection with this resolution in this year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>